<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Hugo&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.hugo.sx/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Hugo&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 23:54:18 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.hugo.sx/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking</title>
      <link>https://blog.hugo.sx/post/blocking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 23:54:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hugo.sx/post/blocking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always find writing like walking up an endless flight of stairs and, as you reach the thousandth stair, using every ounce of energy to pull at your legs to move up just one more stair. Obviously I&amp;rsquo;m exaggerating, or using a bad metaphor, but what I mean is I have a hard time writing. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; at writing; I was a surprisingly good English student, I just .. struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue I&amp;rsquo;ve always had has been blocking. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s the correct term for it but I end up hitting a wall, or a series of taller and taller hurdles. The first one, I jump over easily and the next, and the next, and so on until.. I&amp;rsquo;ll be in the middle of a sentence and I&amp;rsquo;ll just .. &lt;em&gt;backspace&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;backspace&lt;/em&gt; .. I&amp;rsquo;ll delete words, or I&amp;rsquo;ll find myself looking for the perfect word which I&amp;rsquo;ll never end up finding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll stop my train of thought mid sentence, and maybe even loose it in the process, and think of the perfect next word, mostly looking for synonyms. Now, I could just use a thesaurus but that probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why am I writing this blog post? Well, I hope that it might help me figure things out, work out why I always seem to cut myself off. I mean, all of that creative potential just gets botched halfway through. It&amp;rsquo;s also nearly midnight and I can&amp;rsquo;t sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bye.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emails can be bad.</title>
      <link>https://blog.hugo.sx/post/emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 19:57:08 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hugo.sx/post/emails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Email has always been something that I&amp;rsquo;ve needed to keep track, something that since in the back of my mind and something that I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m always worrying about. When I receive an email, it normally means I have to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; something, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s always been the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early last year I made the switch from Gmail to FastMail (one of the best decisions I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far) but it&amp;rsquo;s taken me till now to setup proper rules to sort every single email into folders and memorise all of the keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can safely say that now I&amp;rsquo;m all set up, going &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt; with FastMail and have rules sending emails into their proper folders, I feel less stressed and more in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tend to underestimate how email affects our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned at UNIHACK Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://blog.hugo.sx/post/what-i-learned-at-unihack-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 12:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hugo.sx/post/what-i-learned-at-unihack-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unihack.net/&#34;&gt;UNIHACK Melbourne&lt;/a&gt; is a Melbourne-based hackathon that was run last weekend (August &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;) and is open to all university and TAFE students in Victoria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard &lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; about hackathons, particularly the ones run in the USA, and the amount of creative potential they seem to unleash. You hear the stories about how Facebook Video and Chat &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/video/video.php?v=238358730483&#34;&gt;emerged from hackathons&lt;/a&gt;. This, for me, sounded exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An opportunity to stand out from the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I come up with a fair few ideas every month but, most of the time, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the courage to pursue them, having had failed projects in the past along with the feeling that comes with working on a project for too long (and not making much progress). This hackathon presented an opportunity for me to build something quickly, just a prototype, and an opportunity to stand out from the crowd. The reason I say this could make me stand out is that I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt like a stock-standard programmer - I have experience to do things but, when I browse Github or code that my colleagues write, I feel that I lack the skill they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UNIHACK, like many hackathons, centred itself around a theme, &amp;lsquo;discovery&amp;rsquo;, which made it easier to narrow down what I wanted to build. I came up with the idea for &lt;a href=&#34;http://craft.lc/&#34;&gt;Craft!&lt;/a&gt; about a week before the hackathon began and that week felt like forever, I felt super eager to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gained a number of new skills at the hackathon, not ones that might be particularly useful working in the real world, but would help me achieve personal goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I learned was to time manage, right from the start. I spent a good few hours trying to get a specific part of the code working and, as always, it was one line of code that fixed it. I tend to do this with exams and assignments, where I get stuck on a question for too long and don&amp;rsquo;t move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I found that it&amp;rsquo;s far better to build a simple prototype, completely lacking in features but with one main component (the main idea). Initially, my plan was to build a Minecraft server automator (&amp;lsquo;one-click&amp;rsquo;) with a number of tiered plans (hourly pricing). I thought I could crank out a bunch of features in a short amount of time. I was wrong. I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to discourage anyone reading this, and to clarify, I was working with Python (easy, right?), which I learned a month ago. I was also using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://flask.pocoo.org/&#34;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; framework, which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t touched until a day before the hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third thing I learned is probably the most important - share your ideas. I came into the hackathon intent on keeping my idea to myself, that I would be sharing it a couple days later anyway, everyone could wait. This is entirely the wrong approach. Think about it. You&amp;rsquo;re at a hackathon with a bunch of other like-minded people. They think like you but not &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; like you - so, of course, they could &lt;em&gt;add&lt;/em&gt; to your idea. They might even want to &lt;em&gt;help you work on it&lt;/em&gt;. At a hackathon, sharing will help you flesh out your idea and make new friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one will put you down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about who wins the hackathon (if anyone wins) - the judges are not there so much to criticise but to provide feedback that might help your product function in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>